所以我一直在想，因为我们正在编写一个 Web 服务器
so I've been thinking since we're writing a web server
毕竟不是吗
after all isn't it
大约是时候我们开始从客户端发送我们的请求了
about time we start sending our request from a client
你知道就像一个浏览器
you know like a browser
这是很酷的事情
well here's the cool thing
我们的处理程序模块知道如何转换请求
our handler module knows how to transform requests
浏览器可以显示的响应
into responses that the browser can display
所以我们需要做的就是
so all we need to do
将该处理程序包装在一个薄的套接字层中
is wrap that handler in a thin socket layer
允许任何 hdbb 客户端与我们的服务器交互
that lets any hdbb client interact with our server
我们可以做到
and we can do that
代码量相当有限
with a fairly limited amount of code
通过使用早期的图书馆
by using an early library
这是一个关于 Web 服务器如何工作的快速复习
here's a quick refresher on how a web server works
服务器优先
the server first
创建一个套接字
creates a socket
侦听特定端口上的客户端连接
to listen for client connections on a specific port
数字例如端口 4000
number for example port 4000
您可以将套接字视为通信通道
you can think of a socket as a communication channel
在任何两个程序之间有一个客户端和一个服务器
between any two programs a client and a server
在我们的例子中，我们假设客户端是一个浏览器
in our case we'll assume the client is a browser
虽然它可以是任何 http 客户端
though it could be any http client
创建监听套接字后
after creating the listening socket
服务器等待接受客户端连接
the server waits to accept a client connection
在那个监听套接字上
on that listening socket
发送一个 http 请求
to send an http request
浏览器向服务器发送连接请求
the browser sends a connection request to the server
在端口号上
on the port number
和服务器正在监听的 IP 地址
and ip address where the server is listening
服务器接受连接并创建一个新的
the server accepts the connection and creates a new
客户端套接字
client socket
一个新的插座是
a new socket is
需要，以便服务器可以继续侦听
needed so that the server can continue listening for
监听套接字上的其他连接请求
other connection requests on the listening socket
然后浏览器将http请求发送到服务器
the browser then sends the http request to the server
通过客户端套接字
over the client socket
服务器接收请求生成
the server receives the request generates
出适当的http响应
out an appropriate http response
并将响应发送回浏览器
and sends that response back to the browser
在同一个客户端套接字上
over the same client socket
最后服务器关闭客户端套接字以
finally the server closes the client socket to
结束连接
end the connection
服务器现在是
the server is now
准备好接受下一个连接请求
ready to accept the next connection request
在监听套接字上
on the listening socket
这样
in this way
忽略花里胡哨的东西，比如保持活力
ignoring bells and whistles such as keep alive
就像简单的网络服务器处理一个
as simple web server handles one
一次http请求响应周期
http request response cycle at a time
所以基本上一个网络服务器有
so basically a web server has
两个具有不同职责的独立层
two separate layers with distinct responsibilities
有一个套接字层负责
there's a socket layer that's responsible for
与 hdp 客户端通信
communicating with hdp clients
它不知道如何处理请求
and it doesn't know how to handle requests
所以它将这个责任委托给一个请求
so it delegates that responsibility to a request
第二层的处理程序
handler which is the second layer
负责的处理程序
the handlers responsible for
转换请求字符串
transforming a request string
进入响应字符串
into a response string
它不关心请求来自哪里
and it doesn't care where the request came from
或响应的去向
or where the response is going
现在我们已经有了一个处理模块
now we already have a handler module that
解析和路由请求
parses and router requests
并返回适当的响应
and returns an appropriate response
我们只需要设置一些套接字
we just need to set up some sockets
以便http客户端可以与我们的应用程序交互
so that http clients can interface with our app
通过网络
over the network
为此，我们将使用一个负责处理的套接字库
to do this we'll use a socket library that takes care
所有底层细节
of all the low level details
但它不会是一个长生不老药库
but it won't be an elixir library
因为长生不老药不需要重新发明那个轮子
because elixir doesn't need to reinvent that wheel
early 已经拥有一个经过验证的优秀套接字库
early already has an excellent proven socket library
命名为 jen tcp
named jen tcp
并且该库已预先安装了 elixir
and that library is pre installed with elixir
因为 gen 是一个城市图书馆
since gen is an urban library
它的文件在城市
the documentation for it is at urban
org dock，您会立即注意到
org dock and you'll notice right away at the
上面写着城市
top it says urban
top now top 代表开放的电视广播平台
top now top stands for open telecast platform
这是误导
which is misleading
因为它不是特定于电信的
because it's not specific to telecommunications
但伯爵原本是
but earling was originally
专为构建电信系统而设计
designed for building telecommunication systems
并且经常发生名称卡住
and as often happens the name stuck
那么为什么 top 在今天仍然相关
so why is top still relevant today
事实证明
while it turns out
今天的高可用性系统也有类似的需求
today's high availability systems have similar needs
包括并发的电视广播系统
the telecast systems including concurrency
容错能力和分布
fault tolerant capability and distribution
因为 top 是
and since top was
设计为通用框架
designed as a general purpose framework
一组库和模式
a set of libraries and patterns
它使我们能够构建这些类型的系统
it enables us to build these kinds of systems with
更轻松
greater ease
现在记住这一切始于大约 20 年前
now remember this all started some 20 years ago now
同时
and in the meantime
top 已经发展成为一个久经考验的基础
top has evolved into a battle proven foundation
在其上构建现代应用程序
on which to build modern applications
所以要找到 gntc 我们只需要走到左手边
so to find gntc we just go over to the left hand
导航到这里并点击模块
nav here and click on modules
我们现在看到一堆统治图书馆
and we see a bunch of ruling libraries now
这些库是用裁定写的，但我们可以调用
these libraries are written in ruling but we can call
来自 elixir 的任何统治图书馆
any ruling library from elixir
因为elixir代码被编译成bite代码
because elixir code is compiled into bite code
在催促的虚拟机上运行
that runs on the urging vm
这是
and this is
巨大，因为这意味着长生不老药兼容所有
huge because it means elixir is compatible with all
现有或 lang 库
existing or lang libraries
我们在寻找温柔的图书馆
we're looking for the gentle library
所以我们只需向下滚动
so we just scroll down
这里有很多图书馆
there's a ton of libraries inside of here
下到 gen 部分
go down to the gen section
顺便说一下，当你看到 gen 下划线
and by the way when you see gen underscore
它只代表通用
it just stands for generic
所以我们正在寻找 gen tcp 我会点击它
so we're looking for gen tcp I'll click on it
我们在它说的描述中看到
and we see in the description it says
该模块提供与通信的功能
this module provides functions for communicating with
使用 to 协议的套接字
sockets using the to protocol
这正是我们需要的
which is exactly what we need
现在这个第一个例子在这里
now this first example down here
显示如何在 http 客户端中编写
shows how to write in http client
但我们将使用浏览器作为客户端
but we're going to be using a browser as the client
我们需要写出这个等式的服务器端
we need to write the server side of this equation
所以我要下去
so I'm going to go down
再进一步，有一个服务器示例
a little bit further and there's a server example
我只是要复制这个
and I'm just going to copy this
我们会以此为起点
and we'll use it as a starting point
然后返回并在 lib 调查目录中升华
then back over and sublime in the lib survey directory
我将创建一个名为 http server 的新文件
I'm going to create a new file called http server
ex，然后粘贴该代码
ex and then just paste in that code
现在乍一看，这看起来很熟悉
now at first glance this looks familiar
我们看到的功能与我们在图中看到的相匹配
we see functions matching what we saw in the diagram
所以有一个监听功能
so there's a listen function
一个异常函数
an except function
有这个自定义做接收功能
there's this custom do receive function
接收数据
to receive the data
这就是这个例子所使用的
that's just what this example used
我们将把它改成一分钟后接收
we're going to change that to just receive in a minute
然后我们有关闭功能
and then we have the close function
现在这些是统治功能
now these are ruling functions
我们可以从长生不老药中调用它们
and we can call them from elixir
但我们需要转换或转码
but we need to convert or transcode
这段代码长生不老药
this code to elixir
事实证明这是一个相当简单的
this turns out to be a fairly straightforward
和指导性练习
and instructive exercise
因为作为一个长生不老药开发者
since as an elixir developer
你有时会想要使用
you'll sometimes want to use
现有的早期图书馆
an existing early library
而不是重新发明轮子
instead of reinventing the wheel
所以知道如何调用早期库是值得的
so it pays to know how to call early libraries
从长生不老药我会粘贴它
from elixir I'll paste it
再次注释掉earland代码
again and comment out the earland code
所以我们可以看到差异
so we can see the differences
所以这里的第一行服务器
so this first line here server
这是一个耳区功能
this is an earland function
所以让我们把它改成一个长生不老药函数
so let's just change it to an elixir function
它不需要任何参数，所以它只是 def server 做的
it doesn't take any argument so it's just def server do
现在结束，我要把这些烧焦
and end now I'm going to scorch these over
我们走了，所以第一行在这里
there we go so this first line here
创建一个侦听套接字，它调用侦听来执行此操作
creates a listening socket it calls listen to do that
它将在端口 5 6 7 8
and it's going to be on port 5 6 7 8
然后它有一些选择
and then it has some options
这是方括号中的列表
here's a list in square brackets
现在因为这段代码来自 erling 文档
now since this code comes from erling documentation
它遵循早期命名约定
it follows earling naming conventions
稍微
which are slightly
不同于灵药
different from elixir
因此，让我们逐步将其转码为长生不老药
so let's walk through transcoding it to elixir
第一个我们在左侧有这个元组
1st we have this tuple on the left hand side
我们模式匹配它
and we pattern match it
与我们期望得到的回报相反
against what we expect to be returned
从这个监听函数
from this listen function
现在我们不用担心任何空气状况
now we're not going to worry about any air conditions
所以我们希望这会成功
so we expect this to be successful
所以我们会回来的，你注意到了
so we're going to get back ok and you notice ok
这里都是小写
here is all lowercase
以小写字母开头的井名
well name starting with lowercase letters
早期是原子
in early are atoms
在长生不老药中，我们需要在这里添加一个冒号
in elixir we need to add a colon here
这是一个长生不老药原子
this is an elixir atom
那么元组中的第二个元素就是这个 l sock
then the second element in the tuple is this l sock
这是变量，它将被绑定
and this is the variable and it's going to be bound
到新的监听套接字
to the new listening socket
监听函数返回的东西
the thing returned by the listen function
在早期的变量中以大写字母开头
in variables in earling start with uppercase letters
但在长生不老药中
but in elixir
它们是小写字母
they're lowercase letters
所以我们只是要把它转换成 l sock
so we're just going to convert this to l sock
这就是它
so that's it for the
元组，如果我们来到这里
tuple and if we come over here
我们有 erling 模块 g 然后函数是
we've got the erling module g and then the function is
好好听从 elixir 中引用早期的模块
listen well to reference earlier modules from elixir
我们需要在这里的开头使用冒号
we need to use a colon at the beginning here
所以它将是冒号 g
so it's going to be colon g
然后调用函数
and then to call the function
我们用一个点替换这个冒号
we replace this colon with a dot
就像在 elixir 中调用任何函数一样
so just like calling any function in elixir
我们使用一个点，然后是函数名
we use a dot and then the function name
模块在它之前
the module comes before it
但这里唯一的区别是
but the only difference here is
erelong 模块需要以冒号开头
erelong modules need to start with a colon
他们都是小写的
and they're all lowercase
那么listen函数有两个参数
then the listen function takes two arguments
端口号
the port number
然后是方括号中的选项列表
and then the list of options here in square brackets
好吧，这又是一个
well again this is a
小写二进制，我们知道这是一个原子
lowercase binary and we know that's an atom
在长生不老药的早期，我们必须使用冒号
in early in elixir we have to use a colon
与数据包相同的方式
the same way with packet
并活跃在这里
and active here
所以现在我们有一个列表，其中第一个
so now what we have is a list where the first
元素是亚当二进制
element is an adam binary
第二个元素实际上是一个元组
the second element is actually a tuple
其中第一个元素是一个原子，然后是一个值
where the first element is an atom and then a value
零，然后列表中的第三个元素是
zero and then the third element in the list is
也是一个活跃的元组
also a tuple active
和价值假
and the value false
这会奏效
and that will work
但是在长生不老药中有一种更自动的方法来做到这一点
but there's a more automatic way to do this in elixir
因为我们有一个元组列表
because we have a list of tuples
其中元组的第一项是原子
where the first item of the tuple is an atom
我们可以使用长生不老药关键字列表
we can use an elixir keyword list
如果我们只是去掉花括号，这样做的方法
the way to do that if we just drop the curly braces
在这里，我们把冒号放在这个的另一边
here and we put the colon on the other side of this
所以它是零数据包
so it's packet zero
放下那个花括号然后放在这里
drop that curly brace then down here
脱掉这个
take this off
煤和假
coal and false
并放弃
and drop that
这只是更重要的方法
and that's just the more significant way to do it
但在内部它表示为相同
but internally it's represented as the same
我们开始使用的两个极点列表
list of two poles we started with
不要担心这些选项意味着什么
and don't worry about what these options mean
现在我们将在一分钟内回到那个
right now we'll come back to that in a minute
然后最后这一行的最后一件事是逗号
and then finally the last thing on this line is a comma
在earl中，函数的主体是
and in earl the body of a function is
一个或多个用逗号分隔的早期表达式
one or more early expressions separated by a comma
但我们不需要 elixir 中的逗号
but we don't need the commas in elixir
第二行电话接受
the 2nd line calls accept
暂停它是一个阻塞调用
which suspends it's a blocking call
它等待接受客户端连接
and it waits to accept a client connection
在侦听套接字上，这是这种损失
on the listening socket which is this loss
以及建立连接时
and when a connection is established
此 sock 绑定到新的客户端套接字
this sock is bound to the new client socket
所以让我们继续转换这个
so let's go ahead and convert this
这将是原子好吧
this is going to be the atom okay
这将是一个可变袜子
this is going to be a variable sock
所以小写长生不老药
so lowercase an elixir
结肠起床
colon getup
点除了，这只是
dot except and this is just
l sock，我们可以删除最后的评论
l sock and we can remove the comment at the end
现在在第 3 行我们需要接收请求
now on the 3rd line we need to receive the request
通过从客户端套接字读取来自客户端
from the client by reading from the client socket
在这种情况下是袜子
which is sock in this case
你注意到
and you notice
此示例使用自定义的 do 接收功能
this example uses the custom do receive function
所以让我们继续转换它
so let's go ahead and convert it
这将是亚当
this is going to be adam
好的，这个 bin 变量将被绑定
okay this bin variable is going to be bound
到请求字符串
to the request string
它的名字是 bin 因为它是一个二进制字符串
it's name bin because it's a binary string
这是一个变量
it's a variable
所以我们要把它改成小写的bin
so we're going to change it to a lowercase bin
然后而不是打电话做接收
then instead of calling do receive
在这里我们将调用 go tcp
right here we're going to call go tcp
有一个函数叫做receive re
there's a function called receive r e
我们在那个客户端套接字中传递它
we pass it in that client socket
然后在这里不使用列表
and then instead of using a list here
我们将传入零
we're going to pass in zero
这意味着我们希望收到
that means we want to receive
所有可用的叮咬
all the available bites
所以所有可用的食物都将被退回
so all available bites will be returned
它将被绑定到变量 bin
and it will be bound to the variable bin
然后我们可以在最后去掉那个评论
and then we can get rid of that comment at the end
现在我们有了请求字符串
now that we have the request string
在这里，我们可以继续关闭该客户端套接字
here we can go ahead and close that client socket
所以这将是亚当，好吧
so this is going to be the adam okay
起床点衣服
getup dot clothes
去掉那个逗号，这只是小写套接字
get rid of that comma and this is just lowercase socket
然后这里的最后一行只是返回 bin
and then the final line here just returns bin
这是请求字符串
that's the request string
所以我们将更改为小写 b
so we're changes to a lowercase b
我们可以删除它
and we can remove this
点在最后
dot at the end
获得点意味着我们在函数的末尾
in earning the dot means we're at the end of a function
但我们在长生不老药中不需要它
but we don't need that in elixir
最后我们知道了
finally we know that
所有的 elixir 函数都需要存在于一个模块中
all elixir functions need to live in a module
所以让我们把它放在一个模块中
so let's put this in a module
我们称之为调查 htp 服务器
we'll call it survey htp server
这是我们的功能
there's our function
我们去吧
and there we go
现在让我们使用我们的 http 服务器来进行性爱
now let's take our http server for our spin in sex
所以我们将从
so we'll start with
调查点顶服务器
survey dot top server
点服务器，这是函数的名称
dot server that's the name of the function
好吧
alright
索引挂起，因为它正在等待连接
index hangs because it's waiting for a connection
所以让我们转到浏览器
so let's head over to a browser
我们要去本地主机
and we're going to go to local host
它将是 5 6 7 8
and it's going to be 5 6 7 8
那是港口
that's the port
他注意到说这个页面不起作用
he notices says this page isn't working
本地主机没有发送任何数据
local hosts didn't send any data
那就是
well that's
因为我们的例子实际上并没有
because our example doesn't actually
将响应发送回浏览器
send a response back to the browser
但如果我们回来看看六
but if we come back and look at six
好吧，我们看到它打印了请求
well we see that it prints the request
该服务器函数返回的
that was returned by that server function
记住
remember
服务器函数最后只返回 bin
the server function just returns bin at the end
这就是它收到的请求
and that's the request that it got from
接收所以修复只是打印出来
the receive so fix is just printing out
该请求是一个字符串
that request which is a string
这就是我们在这里看到的
and that's what we're seeing right here
然后就完成了
and then it's done
因为服务端函数只处理一个请求
because the server function only handles one request
这实际上给了我们一个很好的开始来完成它
this actually gives us a great start to finish it off
我们只需要
we simply need to
将有效的 http 响应发送回客户端
send a valid http response back to the client
然后循环
and then loop
回到接受线
back to the accept line
等待下一个连接请求
to wait for the next connection request
所以让我们看看还有什么
so let's look at what a more
完全充实的服务器看起来像
fully fleshed out server would look like
我要贴一些准备好的
I'm going to paste some prepared
替换此文件中当前内容的代码
code to replace what's currently in this file
然后我们要关闭侧边栏
and then we're going to close the sidebar
只是为了我们有更多的空间
just so we have more room
不用担心您会在代码包中找到此代码
don't worry you'll find this code in the code bundle
所以让我们来看看
so let's walk through it
我们提供了相同的模块
we've got the same module served at
http server 然后我们启动这个函数
http server and then we have this function start
我们把它命名为开始
we name it start
而不是像示例代码中那样使用服务器
rather than server as they did in the example code
这只是在给定端口上启动服务器
and this just starts the server on the given port
本地主机
of local host
我们在这里使用了一个保护子句
and we've used a guard clause here
确保端口是整数
to make sure the port is an integer
和
and
并且端口号在十点二十三以上
also that the port number is above ten twenty three
那是因为端口 0 到 10 23
and that's because ports zero through ten twenty three
为操作系统保留
are reserved for the operating system
所以我们需要一个十点二十三以上的港口
so we need a port above ten twenty three
我们使用了守卫爪来强制执行
and we've used the guard claws to enforce that
那么发生的第一件事就是我们调用listen
then the first thing that happens is we call listen
就像我们在示例中所做的那样
just like we did in the example
它会创建一个套接字
and it's going to create a socket to
监听客户端连接
listen for client connections
所以这个监听套接字变量是绑定的
and so this listen socket variable is bound
到监听套接字
to the listening socket
正如我们之前看到的
as we saw before
监听端口有两个参数
listen takes two arguments the port
然后是选项列表
and then a list of options
所以这类似于我们之前的选项
so this is similar to the options we had before
但我们改变了其中的几个
but we've changed a couple of these
那么这些选项实际上意味着什么
so what do these options actually mean
我们不必真正担心这些细节
we don't have to really worry about these details
因为你会用
because you'll use
不同场景下的不同选择
different options in different scenarios
但是让我们来看看这些
but let's walk through these
这个二元期权
this binary option
表示我们要以二进制模式打开套接字
means we want to open the socket in binary mode
并将数据作为二进制文件交付
and deliver data as binaries
然后第二个选项是这个数据包原始
and then the second option is this packet raw
这意味着我们希望将整个二进制文件交付给我们
which means we want the entire binary deliver to us
没有在幕后发生任何数据包处理
without any packet handling happening behind the scenes
然后我们有这个活动的假
then we have this active false which
意味着我们想在准备好时接收数据
means we want to receive data when we're ready
通过调用 g 接收
by calling g receive
我们马上就会看到
which we'll look at in just a minute
最后我们有了这个
and then finally we have this
重用地址设置为真
reused address set to true
这意味着我们希望允许重用
which means we want to allow reusing the
监听器崩溃时的地址
address if the listener crashes
这些是简单的标准选项
and these are pretty standard options for a simple
然后我们打印出我们正在监听的网络服务器
web server then we print out that we're listening for
该端口上的连接
connections on that port
然后我们进入except循环
and then we drop into the except loop
所以这只是一个名为 except 循环的函数
so this is just a function called except loop
我们将监听套接字传递给它
we pass it the listen socket
这将接受客户端连接
and this is going to accept client connections
在这个监听套接字上
on this listen socket
我们打印出来
we print out that
我们正在等待接受客户端连接
we're waiting to accept a client connection
然后我们打电话
and then we call
就像我们在前面的示例代码中看到的一样接受
accept just like we saw in the example code earlier
记住它暂停或
remember it suspends or
阻塞并等待客户端连接
blocks and waits for a client connection
以及何时接受该连接
and when that connection is accepted
然后这个客户端套接字被绑定
then this client socket is bound
到新的客户端套接字
to the new client socket
那么那么
so then
我们刚刚宣布连接被接受
we just pronounced that the connection was accepted
然后我们称这个函数为serve
and then we call this function serve
它将接收请求
which is going to receive the request
关闭该客户端套接字并发送回响应
off that client socket and send a response back
通过该客户端套接字
over that client socket
一旦返回
and once this returns
然后我们将再次调用接受循环
then we're going to call accept loop again
递归循环到这里
recursively to loop back up here
并等待下一个客户端连接
and wait for the next client connection
所以让我们深入研究这个服务功能
so let's dive into this serve function
好吧，这里需要客户端套接字
well it takes the client socket here
将其输入芦苇请求
pipes it into reed request
这将把请求作为字符串返回
that's going to return the request as a string
然后我们管它
then we pipe it
在这个函数中生成响应，所以我们生成一个
in this function generate response so we generate a
有效的 http 响应
valid http response
然后我们通过管道将其转化为正确的响应
and then we pipe it into right response
把它写回来
to write it back out
通过该客户端套接字
over that client socket
读取请求非常简单，它调用 gnpc 接收
read request is pretty simple it calls gnpc receive
在该客户端套接字上传入零
on that client socket passing in zero
这意味着我们想要所有可用的食物
which means we want all the available bites
然后
then
请求将绑定到这个变量
the request is going to get bound to this variable
我们从这里函数返回的请求
request which we return from this function here
所以返回的是我们的请求字符串
so the return of this is our request string
然后我们通过管道生成响应
which we then pipe into generate response
生成响应只返回这个
generate response just returns this
通用 http 响应
generic http response
你注意到我们实际上是
you notice we're actually
忽略这里的请求，因为我们真的不在乎
ignoring the request here because we don't really care
我们只是生成一个
we're just generating a
听到码头返回
hear dock to return
一个有效的 http 响应，只是说你好
a valid http response that just says hello
以便返回响应
so that returns the response
在这里得到正确的回应
here which gets piped into right response
如果我们看看那个
if we have a look at that
它在客户端套接字中接收响应
it takes the response in a client socket
调用 gntc 发送
calls gntc send
在那个客户端套接字上给它响应
on that client socket giving it the response
我们假设这是成功的
and we assume that that's successful
所以我们将其模式匹配到好的
so we pattern match it to okay
我们说嘿我们发回了回复
we say hey we sent the response back
然后我们关闭了那个客户端套接字
and then we closed that client socket
所以然后备份到这里
so then back up here
这里的管道完成了，这就是服务部分
this pipeline here is done that's the serve part
这返回
this returns
然后我们循环回来在这里接受循环
and then we loop back up to accept loop here
这让我们回到了这里
which takes us back up here
我们正在等待下一个客户端连接
and we're waiting for the next client connection
所以这基本上就是我们所看到的
so this is basically what we saw
在前面的例子中，我们
in the early example we
超越较早
transcended earlier
我们刚刚添加了一堆
we just added a bunch
评论和一些打印声明
of comments and some print statements
展示正在发生的事情
to demonstrate what's happening
我们还添加了部分
we also added the part
它在哪里发送有效的 hdp 响应
where it sends a valid hdp response
退出
back out
通过客户端套接字
over the client socket
另一个重要的
the other important
我们所做的改变是我们递归调用
change we made is that we recursively call
接受循环，以便服务器可以继续接受
accept loops so the server can continue to accept
新的连接请求
new connection requests
现在让我们使用这个版本的代码进行旋转，我
now let's take this version of our code for spin and I
X
x
这是调查高清服务器
it's survey hd server
我们调用了我们的函数 start 并且它需要一个端口
we called our function start and it takes a port
我将使用端口 4000
I'm going to use port 4000
你可以使用任何你想要的超过十个端口
you can use whatever port you want above ten
二十三
twenty three
好的，它启动了
okay it starts up
我们看到它正在监听连接请求
and we see that it's listening for connection requests
在端口 4000
on port 4000
它正在等待接受下一个客户端连接
and it's waiting to accept the next client connection
那就是那个阻塞电话，除了那里
that's that blocking call except right there
所以现在如果我们浏览到本地主机
so now if we browse over to local host
4000 那是我们的港口
4000 that's our port
我要做斜线熊
I'm going to do slash bears
看看我们得到你好这是我们的一般反应
look at that we get hello that's our generic response
如果我们向上滚动，则返回 ix
and back over an ix if we scroll up
它就在这里等着
it was waiting right here
但是当我们发送请求时
but then when we sent the request in
连接被接受
the connection was accepted
它在这里收到了这个关于斜线熊的请求
it received this request right here for slash bears
所以这是完整的http请求
so here's the full http request
然后它把响应发回
and then it sent the response back out
我们在这里的一般回应
our generic response here
然后它掠夺回来
and then it loot back up
它正在等待下一个客户端连接
and it's waiting for the next client connection
很酷，所以我们的通用 http 服务器正在运行
cool so our generic http server is going
通过所有正确的动作
through all the correct motions
现在我们需要做的就是插入我们的请求处理程序
now all we need to do is plug in our request handler
进入这个管道
into this pipeline
所以不要在这里生成通用响应
so instead of generating a generic response right here
我们想打电话调查
we want to call survey
把手把手
handle handle
所以会发生什么
so what's going to happen
被读取
is read
要求
request
将从客户端套接字获取请求
is going to get the request from the client socket
然后它将通过管道传输该字符串
then it's going to pipe that string
进入我们的句柄函数
into our handle function
它将响应作为字符串返回
which returns the response as the string
然后将该响应字符串通过管道传输到
and that response string is then piped into
正确的反应
right response
它将响应发送回
which sends the response back out
通过客户端套接字
over the client socket
换句话说
in other words
我们已经将处理程序包裹在一个薄薄的
we've wrapped our handler in a thin
允许的套接字层
socket layer that lets
与我们服务器的任何 http 客户端接口
any http client interface with our server
所以让我们再运行一次
so let's run this again
现在我的性爱会议挂了
now my sex session is hung
因为它正在等待客户端连接
because it's waiting for a client connection
所以我要
so I'm just going to
控制 c 两次以摆脱它
control c twice to get out of that
并重新启动 ix
and start ix back up again
然后我们将再次在端口 4000 上启动我们的服务器
then we'll start our server on port 4000 again
好的，它正在等待客户端连接
okay it's waiting for a client connection
reload 本地主机 4000 斜线熊
reload local host 4000 slash bears
看看我们得到了所有熊的列表
and look at that we get a list of all of the bears
很酷，所以现在我们知道它正在调用我们的处理程序
cool so now we know it's calling our handler
所以它可以在他们的浏览器上运行，但现在
so it works on their browser but now
任何 http 客户端都可以与我们的 Web 服务器交互
any http client can interface with our web server
实际上
in fact
我们可以使用 curl 命令行客户端发送一个
we can use the curl command line client to send an
api 请求所以我只是在一个新的终端会话中
api request so I'm just in a new terminal session here
我将使用 curl
I'm going to use curl
然后我要给它 http 本地主机 4000 api
and then I'm going to give it http local host 4000 api
斜线熊，我们得到一个熊的json列表
slash bears and we get back a json list of bears
这很甜蜜
that's pretty sweet
自从伯爵
since earling has
已经存在了几十年
been around for decades
它有大量经过验证的真实库
it has an extensive set of tried and true libraries
这是值得牢记的
this is something worth keeping in mind
如果您没有找到适合您需求的长生不老药库
if you don't find an elixir library to suit your needs
寻找伯爵图书馆
look for an earling library
可能性是如果它是通用需求
odds are if it's a general purpose need
有人已经写了一个库
somebody has already written a library
现在你知道如何使用了
and now you know how to use
长生不老药包装中的任何统治图书馆
any ruling library in your elixir wrap